Sam Tanner

Seattle, WA | samuel.m.s.tanner@gmail.com | github.com/samueltanner | linkedin.com/in/samueltanner/

Software Developer

Entrepreneur turned software developer. My last decade was spent honing skills in sales, marketing, design, and business development, now I am taking the creativity, determination, and gusto those competencies required and applying them to web development. I thrive in an environment where I push the limits of my comfort zone; learn rapidly with a collaborative team; and produce beautiful, efficient, and novel solutions.

Skills

Technical: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Vue.js, HTML, CSS, PostgresSQL, Git, Testing, Pair-Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, API's, Bootstrap

Additional: Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom, etc.), Logic Pro, Airtable, Microsoft Excel

Education

Actualize Coding Bootcamp

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development | January 2021 - May 2021

- Capstone Project Funny Money: personally built a web app that allows users to submit, track, and share equity
 positions of publicly traded equities. Funny Money's goal is to be a place where users can share specific details of
 their investment portfolio with friends and peers. The app was built on a Rails backend, a Vue.js frontend, and utilized
 free API's to access real-time market information.
- Bootcamp: Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
 - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
 - Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
 - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes

University of Washington

Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration, Focus in Entrepreneurship | 2012 - 2016

Experience

Joe Chocolate Co. | March 2016 - December 2020

Co-Founder & CEO

- Started business as an undergraduate class project and a two-man operation out of the back of a fish-n-chips restaurant
- Managed up to 24 different employees in departments ranging from sales and marketing to production and fulfillment
- Built and implemented software for internal and external websites, CRM, fulfillment, automated email marketing, and sales forecasting which increased efficiency and decreased customer wait-times
- Expanded wholesale business 300+ locations including REI, Whole Foods, and Nordstrom
- Opened retail location in Pike Place Market and created a cross-platform PoS and digital marketing sales funnel
- Completed four rounds of funding from angel investors and private equity totalling over \$1.6M

Caveman Dirtbag Sponsorship | May 2016 - May 2020 Founder

- Created first-of-its-kind sponsorship for thru-hikers on the Pacific Crest Trail
- Utilized paid and unpaid social media marketing strategies to reach aspiring hikers from around the globe
- Partnered with and managed co-sponsors like Arc'Teryx and Patagonia to compile cash and gear for hikers
- Enhanced shipping software to automate the delivery of care-packages to hikers at remote locations along the Pacific Crest Trail

Peach | August 2016 - November 2016

Business Development Associate

- Performed sales cycle from discovery, to cold calling, to activation of lunch delivery program using Salesforce
- Onboarded 30+ businesses onto Peach's lunch delivery platform including two of Seattle's largest hospitals, JP Morgan, and Weyerhaeuser's headquarters

CardSwapper | February 2013 - June 2016

Co-Founder & CEO

- Co-founded business as an undergraduate freshman at the University of Washington
- Grew and managed team of 12 developers and designers
- Designed and wire-framed multiple versions of a mobile application and website
- Led teams to launch mobile app on iOS store and web
- Partnered with the nation's largest gift card liquidation platform to expand functionality of iOS app

University of Washington School of Music | October 2013 - May 2016 Student Visual and Audio Archiver

- Recorded, live-mixed, and produced live classical, jazz, choral, and orchestral performances in high-fidelity
- Developed proficiency in Logic Pro, Audacity, and Premiere Pro to increase quality of archived audio and video
- Contracted independently by graduate students to record, produce, and master thesis performances

TangoCard | June 2013 - August 2013

Social Media Summer Intern

- Managed corporate Facebook, Twitter, and Linkedin social profiles via Hootsuite
- Deployed unpaid social marketing strategies to increase following across platforms by nearly 50%